<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trieste on Math Life</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/trieste/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trieste on Math Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:00:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/trieste/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Two nights at Cattinara (in Spanish)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/two-nights-at-cattinara/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/two-nights-at-cattinara/</guid>
      <description>En junio de 2023 al volver de un viaje a Viena y Amsterdam empecé con síntomas de un resfrío fuerte. Pero la fiebre no bajaba y después de unos días llamamos al servicio médico. Terminé yendo en ambulancia al pronto soccorso del Ospedale di Cattinara en Trieste. Tenía una fea pulmonía.&#xA;Mientras estuve en el hospital escribí las notas que siguen.&#xA;Me llama mucho la atención las jerarquías dentro del hospital marcadas por uniformes de varios colores.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saxes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/saxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/saxes/</guid>
      <description>Walking to the riva after getting gelato at Marco. Maybe these musicians were part of the ensemble playing on the temporary stage on Piazza Unita related to the Pope&amp;rsquo;s visit to Trieste. Enjoying the sun and the ocean breeze during a break.&#xA;Saxes </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/boat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/boat/</guid>
      <description>I think this is the first picture I took focusing on a reflected image in water. I liked the way the masts of the boats (straight, solid, crucial to their life) appeared in this surrealistic, impressionistic way. Since then when walking around Trieste near the sea or the canal I always look at the scenes reflected on their surface and often take a picture. It is now trivial to rotate and flip the picture so we get a interesting view from a very weird angle.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
