<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Math on Math Life</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/math/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Math on Math Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Special parameters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/tmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/tmp/</guid>
      <description>type:: note kind:: Math title:: Special parameters, work of Woldemar Heymann 1 author:: Fernando Rodriguez Villegas project:: HGM tags:: date:: Oct 8th, 2024&#xA;An old paper (Über hypergeometrische Funktionen, deren letztes Element speziell ist.) (from a talk by Wadym Zudilin) discusses the value of an ${}_2F_1$ at special $t$&amp;rsquo;s. He does $t=-1/3,1/4,1/5$ and mentions Gauss for $t=1,-1,1/2$ and Kummer for $t=-1/8,1/9,8/9$.&#xA;$$ F_h = F \left( -\frac{h}{2}, -\frac{h}{2} + \frac{1}{2}, h + \frac{3}{2}, -\frac{1}{3} \right) = \frac{2}{3} \cdot \left( \frac{8}{9} \right)^h \cdot \frac{\Gamma \left( \frac{1}{3} \right) \cdot \Gamma \left( h + \frac{3}{2} \right)}{\sqrt{\pi} \cdot \Gamma \left( h + \frac{4}{3} \right)} $$ If we take $h=1/2$ we get an HGM defined over $\mathbb Q$ with gamma vector $[-4,1,1,2]$ and corresponding Weierstrass model $$ y^2+xy=x^3+\frac t{64}x.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Number Theory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/book/</guid>
      <description>This book, published in 2007, is a discussion of various mathematical experiments in Number Theory using the computer. The main computational tool used is the sophisticated package PARI-GP. Maybe the best way to describe the book in more detail is to just quote its preface.&#xA;Preface -------- There is a long and distinguished tradition in mathematics, perhaps even more pronounced in number theory, whereas a chance discovery of a pattern or identity between numbers arising from unrelated calculations leads to the development of whole new fields (this is precisely how Gauss phrases it in a diary entry).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Articles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/math-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/math-articles/</guid>
      <description>Below you can access all my math research articles. Most of them are published but not all.&#xA;Bibliography Quaternionic extensions Rodriguez Villegas, F. (in Spanish). In: Proceedings of the IV Coloquio Latinoamericano De Algebra, Mendoza, Argentina, (1984). Quaternionic extensions and rotations Rodriguez Villegas, F. (In Spanish). Notas De La Sociedad Matemática De Chile, 5(1), 201–202, (1986). Relations between quadratic forms and certain Galois extensions Rodriguez Villegas, F. (Unpublished). (1987). On the square root of special values of certain L-series Rodriguez Villegas, F.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
