<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Math on Math Life</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/math/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Math on Math Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Special parameters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/math-notes/special-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/math-notes/special-parameters/</guid>
      <description>An old paper (Über hypergeometrische Funktionen, deren letztes Element speziell ist) by W. Heymann (from a talk by Wadim Zudilin) discusses the value of an ${}_2F_1$ at special $t$&amp;rsquo;s. He does $t=-1/3,1/4,1/5$ and related values and mentions Gauss for $t=1,-1,1/2$ and Kummer for $t=-1/8,1/9,8/9$.&#xA;For example we have this identity $$ F_h = F \left( -\frac{h}{2}, -\frac{h}{2} + \frac{1}{2}, h + \frac{3}{2}, -\frac{1}{3} \right) = \frac{2}{3} \cdot \left( \frac{8}{9} \right)^h \cdot \frac{\Gamma \left( \frac{1}{3} \right) \cdot \Gamma \left( h + \frac{3}{2} \right)}{\sqrt{\pi} \cdot \Gamma \left( h + \frac{4}{3} \right)} $$ If we take $h=1/2$ we get an HGM defined over $\mathbb Q$, we get the gamma vector $[-4,1,1,2]$ and corresponding Weierstrass model $$ y^2+xy=x^3+\frac t{64}x.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HGM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/hgm/hgm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/hgm/hgm/</guid>
      <description>This project got started at a fabulous workshop held in Benasque, Spain (in the mountains, a few hours drive from Barcelona) in 2009. I wrote this post in my blog after returning from another workshop there on p-adic analysis in 2007. In my own notes I added:&#xA;The place is truly amazing. Mountains falling over you as you walk down the street.&#xA;The plan of the 2009 workshop was to explore ways to compute exotic L-functions, not arising from elliptic curves or usual modular forms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamilton and the Discovery of Quaternions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/hamilton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/hamilton/</guid>
      <description>Towards the end of my Ph.D. years at The Ohio State University together with a bunch of graduate students we thought of publishing our own magazine. We struggled to come up with a good name for it so after a lot of back and forth we settled on &amp;ldquo;The Empy Set&amp;rdquo;. The OSU graduate advisor found this too nihilistic and wanted us to pick a different name. We nevertheless wrote what inevitably ended up being the only issue of &amp;ldquo;The Empty Set&amp;rdquo; and circulated it among the department.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benasque</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/benasque/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/benasque/</guid>
      <description>While I wait for my brain strings to settle after a long summer shuttling about I make a quick core dump before it’s all gone.&#xA;I spent two weeks in Benasque, Spain for the workshop P-adic analysis, Periods and Physics . We ended up being a very small group of participants, unfortunate in a way but the result was a very charming workshop. And what a place! Benasque is in a valley in the Spanish Pyrenees not far from the border with France, a small mountain town where you walk everywhere, surrounded by amazing mountains full of unbelievably beautiful hikes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>K-theory and L-functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/k-theory-l-fctns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/k-theory-l-fctns/</guid>
      <description>These are notes (taken by M. Lalín) for a course on $K$-theory and $L$-functions I gave at Harvard University in the Spring of 2002. Notes for the first few lectures were taken by S. Valverde.&#xA;The main goal of the course was to explain how to frame conceptually the numerical examples of D. Boyd relating the Mahler measure of certain two variable polynomials $A(x,y)$ and $L(E,2)$ for $E$ the elliptic curve defined by the zeros of $A$.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La Función Zeta de Hasse-Weil (in Spanish)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/weil-zeta-merida/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 1999 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/weil-zeta-merida/</guid>
      <description>These are notes for a course in Spanish on the Hasse-Weil zeta function given en Mérida, Venezuela in 1999.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bernoulli Polynomials</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/manuscripts/bernoulli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 1989 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/manuscripts/bernoulli/</guid>
      <description>These are notes on approaching Bernoulli polynomials as eigenvalues of certain operators acting on polynomials. It is my re-interpretation of work of E. H. Lehmer. (A new approach to Bernoulli polynomials, Amer. Math. Monthly 95(1988), 905-911.) I wrote this note at the end of my Ph.D. studies around 1989.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
