<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Public Lectures on Math Life</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Public Lectures on Math Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 12:36:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Mathematics of the Football</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/math-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/math-football/</guid>
      <description>I gave some version of this lecture on the Mathematics of the football/soccer ball several times, in different places and in various languages.&#xA;Florence 20/05/2024 Gonit Sora (online) 14/06/2021 Form their website:&#xA;Gonit Sora is a multi lingual (English and Assamese) web magazine devoted to publishing well written and original articles related to science in general and mathematics in particular.&#xA;One of its founders and current editor is Manjil P. Saikia, a former ICTP Diploma student, who invited me to give this online talk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/blet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/blet/</guid>
      <description>In 2018 I was invited by my former ICTP Diploma student Manjil P. Saikia to give a mini-course at the University of Vienna. I also gave a general talk about the puzzle Blet. Later in the year I have a Basic Notions Seminar on the puzzle at ICTP.&#xA;As an experiment I got the transcript of the talk from youtube and then ran it through ChatGPT. After some light editing here is the result.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liceo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/2015-liceo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/2015-liceo/</guid>
      <description>Frequently groups of high-school students come to visit ICTP. One of their standard activities is to attend a short talk by a scientist. A number of times I gave one of these talks. In this case it was a talk for Italian students and I discussed a bit the mathematics of information transmission.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impartial Games</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/impartial-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/impartial-games/</guid>
      <description>I gave a the kick-off Basic Notions talk at ICTP in 2014 on Impartial Games (one of the topics of the course Math, Puzzles and Computers).&#xA;I expected students in the class to connect to puzzles and eventually to the corresponding mathematics through a chilhood experience. It is certainly what happened to me while preparing the lectures.&#xA;I have a somewhat vague but powerful memory of being introduced to the standard version of the game of Nim at an early age.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Morning Math Group</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/smmg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2007 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/smmg/</guid>
      <description>At UT Austin there is a wonderful program of lectures for high-school students on some Saturday mornings. I gave a number of the talks there including one about lattice polygons and the number 12.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
