<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Math Life</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Math Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 10:00:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Belluno</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/belluno/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/belluno/</guid>
      <description>En Belluno para el famoso PET. Casi cuatro horas de tren desde Trieste. Lindo paisaje de montaña, nieve en las cimas a lo lejos.&#xA;Belluno bonita en el sol brillante y el aire límpido. Claramente del Veneto, extraño Venezia en las montañas. Piazza dei Martiri antes fuera delle mura de la ciudad. Un cono de nieve sucia a la sombra de unos árboles en la plaza. Piazza arcuata, edificios en curva a 92 m de la muralla, dos metros mas que el alcance de los arcabuses de la época.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to eat a maritozzo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/how-to-eat-a-maritozzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/how-to-eat-a-maritozzo/</guid>
      <description>The first thing to understand is that the question of the title is not a trivial one, especially if you have a beard.&#xA;So what is a maritozzo? It&amp;rsquo;s a Roman pastry consisting of a ball of sweet bread with a big gash in the middle completely filled with whipped cream. The New York Times calls them unnapealingly &amp;ldquo;Sweet Cream Buns&amp;rdquo;, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t even begin to do them justice. It seems that maritozzi have become quite a thing in the US from what I can gather online.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mushrooms with blue cheese</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cooking/mushrooms-blue-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cooking/mushrooms-blue-cheese/</guid>
      <description>I am not sure where I got this from. I do remember my aunt, the writer Alicia Plante, back in Buenos Aires, mentioning a recipe of baked fish with blue cheese that I prepared a few times. In the US I adapted it using big mushrooms instead of fish. But maybe I got the idea somewhere.&#xA;1 Get some big round mushrooms, for example, shitake mushrooms. I read that one should never wash the mushrooms with water as they get ruined somehow but gently remove any impurities with a soft brush.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pasta verde</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cooking/pasta-verde/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cooking/pasta-verde/</guid>
      <description>After a fair number of iterations this is the result of my cooking pasta with greens. At home we just call it Pasta Verde. This version is with Swiss chard but a real nice combination is dandelion leaves (tarassaco in Italian) and Swiss chard (bieta). You can see how the various steps follow those for cooking a risotto.&#xA;1 Start preparing about an hour in advance a thick broth to use to cook the pasta.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potatoes and Swiss chard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cooking/potato-chard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cooking/potato-chard/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago after an invited seminar talk at ISTA in Vienna we went with my host Tamas Hausel and some of his group for dinner to a Croatian restaurant. I had fish I think and a side dish of potatoes and chard, which I really loved. I have been trying to reproduce it from memory ever since. I found out later (while on vacation in Lussinpicolo) that it is actually a standard traditional dish in Croacia known as blitva (which simply means chard).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special parameters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/math-notes/special-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/math-notes/special-parameters/</guid>
      <description>An old paper (Über hypergeometrische Funktionen, deren letztes Element speziell ist) by W. Heymann (from a talk by Wadim Zudilin) discusses the value of an ${}_2F_1$ at special $t$&amp;rsquo;s. He does $t=-1/3,1/4,1/5$ and related values and mentions Gauss for $t=1,-1,1/2$ and Kummer for $t=-1/8,1/9,8/9$.&#xA;For example we have this identity $$ F_h = F \left( -\frac{h}{2}, -\frac{h}{2} + \frac{1}{2}, h + \frac{3}{2}, -\frac{1}{3} \right) = \frac{2}{3} \cdot \left( \frac{8}{9} \right)^h \cdot \frac{\Gamma \left( \frac{1}{3} \right) \cdot \Gamma \left( h + \frac{3}{2} \right)}{\sqrt{\pi} \cdot \Gamma \left( h + \frac{4}{3} \right)} $$ If we take $h=1/2$ we get an HGM defined over $\mathbb Q$, we get the gamma vector $[-4,1,1,2]$ and corresponding Weierstrass model $$ y^2+xy=x^3+\frac t{64}x.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxford</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/oxford/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/oxford/</guid>
      <description>I was back in Oxford to give a talk at the workshop on The P=W Conjecture in Non Abelian Hodge Theory, part of the Clay Mathematical Institute conference of 2024.&#xA;I arrived a day early, on Saturday, and spent the day walking around town remembering the old days (2009-2010 when I visited for the year). There was some kind of graduation ceremony happening and though I don&amp;rsquo;t really like to take pictures of people I could not resist this one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two nights at Cattinara (in Spanish)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/two-nights-at-cattinara/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/two-nights-at-cattinara/</guid>
      <description>En junio de 2023 al volver de un viaje a Viena y Amsterdam empecé con síntomas de un resfrío fuerte. Pero la fiebre no bajaba y después de unos días llamamos al servicio médico. Terminé yendo en ambulancia al pronto soccorso del Ospedale di Cattinara en Trieste. Tenía una fea pulmonía.&#xA;Mientras estuve en el hospital escribí las notas que siguen.&#xA;Me llama mucho la atención las jerarquías dentro del hospital marcadas por uniformes de varios colores.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MFO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/mfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/mfo/</guid>
      <description>I have been going to Oberwolfach for a number of years now, twice for two weeks at a time in the Research in Pairs scheme. What an incredible place, a real gem.&#xA;MFO </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Number Theory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/book/</guid>
      <description>This book, published in 2007, is a discussion of various mathematical experiments in Number Theory using the computer. The main computational tool used is the sophisticated package PARI-GP. Maybe the best way to describe the book in more detail is to just quote its preface.&#xA;Preface -------- There is a long and distinguished tradition in mathematics, perhaps even more pronounced in number theory, whereas a chance discovery of a pattern or identity between numbers arising from unrelated calculations leads to the development of whole new fields (this is precisely how Gauss phrases it in a diary entry).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Randomness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/on-randomness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/on-randomness/</guid>
      <description>Iperborea is an italian publishing house founded by Emilia Lodigiani in 1987 which aims to bring to Italian readers the literature of northern Europe. Their books have a distinctive format and texture of their covers making them instantly recognizable while browsing in a bookstore. Not all of their titles are easy to find in English in Italy so they are a good way for me to connect to Scandinavian culture while also practicing my Italian.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beware</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/beware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/beware/</guid>
      <description>I was on the bus 6 coming back from ICTP. We had stopped at the light at the end of Barcola. Looking out the window I noticed the hand in the car next to the bus, sticking out to avoid getting the smoke inside the car. I never saw the person&amp;rsquo;s face. The hand looked scary.&#xA;Boat </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HGM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/hgm/hgm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/hgm/hgm/</guid>
      <description>This project got started at a fabulous workshop held in Benasque, Spain (in the mountains, a few hours drive from Barcelona) in 2009. I wrote this post in my blog after returning from another workshop there on p-adic analysis in 2007. In my own notes I added:&#xA;The place is truly amazing. Mountains falling over you as you walk down the street.&#xA;The plan of the 2009 workshop was to explore ways to compute exotic L-functions, not arising from elliptic curves or usual modular forms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamilton and the Discovery of Quaternions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/hamilton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/hamilton/</guid>
      <description>Towards the end of my Ph.D. years at The Ohio State University together with a bunch of graduate students we thought of publishing our own magazine. We struggled to come up with a good name for it so after a lot of back and forth we settled on &amp;ldquo;The Empy Set&amp;rdquo;. The OSU graduate advisor found this too nihilistic and wanted us to pick a different name. We nevertheless wrote what inevitably ended up being the only issue of &amp;ldquo;The Empty Set&amp;rdquo; and circulated it among the department.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saxes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/saxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/saxes/</guid>
      <description>Walking to the riva after getting gelato at Marco. Maybe these musicians were part of the ensemble playing on the temporary stage on Piazza Unita related to the Pope&amp;rsquo;s visit to Trieste. Enjoying the sun and the ocean breeze during a break.&#xA;Saxes </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Large Language Model in the 1700s?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/jonathan-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/jonathan-swift/</guid>
      <description>I listened to a fascinating podcast in the &amp;ldquo;Past, Present, Future&amp;rdquo; series by David Runciman on the 1726 satire &amp;ldquo;Gulliver&amp;rsquo;s Travels&amp;rdquo; by Jonathan Swift. Runciman gives an excellent summary of the various journeys that Gulliver undertakes in this book; journeys to far away lands were he encounters fantastic creatures and their world: tiny people, giants, talking horses, and the like.&#xA;In one of these journeys Gulliver finds academics stubbornly determined to strip language of all ambiguity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Something about cheese</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/something-about-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/something-about-cheese/</guid>
      <description>I love this picture.&#xA;Early in the morning in the Barrio Gotico of Barcelona. As I walked by I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help hearing part of the conversation. The young woman seemed to be asking in good but accented Spanish where she could find a particular kind of cheese. I imagine she thought the old ladies were locals that would know.&#xA;Something about cheese </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mathematics of the Football</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/math-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/math-football/</guid>
      <description>I gave some version of this lecture on the Mathematics of the football/soccer ball several times, in different places and in various languages.&#xA;Florence 20/05/2024 Gonit Sora (online) 14/06/2021 Form their website:&#xA;Gonit Sora is a multi lingual (English and Assamese) web magazine devoted to publishing well written and original articles related to science in general and mathematics in particular.&#xA;One of its founders and current editor is Manjil P. Saikia, a former ICTP Diploma student, who invited me to give this online talk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counting quiver representations over finite fields</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/quivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/quivers/</guid>
      <description>These are notes (taken by E. Vitale) of a summer school held at the University of Bologna in the week of 22-26 May, 2023 as part of the program Quiver Representations, Quiver Varieties and Combinatorics.&#xA;This is the announcement for the course.&#xA;Counting representations of quivers over finite fields In these lectures I will present the calculation of the title in the case of the star-shaped quivers related to character varieties based on my joint work with E.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/boat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/boat/</guid>
      <description>I think this is the first picture I took focusing on a reflected image in water. I liked the way the masts of the boats (straight, solid, crucial to their life) appeared in this surrealistic, impressionistic way. Since then when walking around Trieste near the sea or the canal I always look at the scenes reflected on their surface and often take a picture. It is now trivial to rotate and flip the picture so we get a interesting view from a very weird angle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Figs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/figs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/figs/</guid>
      <description>Let’s talk figs.&#xA;There was a fig tree near the main house “Villa Isaura” in Carlos Paz, Cordoba where I spent many a holiday as a kid. I remember breaking off leaves to see and feel the white sticky substance that came out. It was a somewhat mysterious and out of the way tree, with strange gnarly branches and big dark green leaves, a huge contrast to the tall, straight and ubiquitous eucalyptus trees that lined up so many sidewalks of my Buenos Aires childhood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From here to there</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/from-here-to-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/from-here-to-there/</guid>
      <description>One of the odd perks of getting old is that one can look back to the distant past and wonder with cold detachment just who the hell we were.&#xA;As a kid I was obsessed with cryptography and secret messages. I even halfheartedly tried to create a language that only my friends and I would understand. I wanted to build a robot. I also wanted to live in a desert island and made endless plans in my head on how I would run my life on it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixed Hodge Numbers and Factorial Ratios</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/duke-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/duke-conf/</guid>
      <description>These are the slides of my talk at Bill Duke&amp;rsquo;s birthday conference held at ETH in Zurich. I later wrote an extended abstract of this talk. It includes a proof of the calculation of the mixed Hodge numbers of a hypergeometric motive. The original conjecture on Hodge numbers of is a paper of Corti and Golyshev. A proof was given by Fedorov.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/blet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/blet/</guid>
      <description>In 2018 I was invited by my former ICTP Diploma student Manjil P. Saikia to give a mini-course at the University of Vienna. I also gave then a general talk about the puzzle Blet. Later in the year I gave a Basic Notions Seminar on the puzzle at ICTP.&#xA;As an experiment I got the transcript of the talk from youtube and then ran it through ChatGPT. After some light editing here is the result.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hypergeometric Motives II</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/2018-rh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/2018-rh/</guid>
      <description>These are the slides of my talk at the 2018 conference &amp;ldquo;Perspectives on the Riemann Hypothesis&amp;rdquo; held in Bristol.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hypergeometric Motives I</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/beeger-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/beeger-lecture/</guid>
      <description>These are the slides of my Beeger Lecture at the 2018 Dutch Mathematical Congress.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HGM: Some hyperelliptic curves</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/hgm-hyperell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/hgm-hyperell/</guid>
      <description>These are notes of a talk a gave in a workshop on the arithmetic of curves held in Barcelona in 2017.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liceo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/2015-liceo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/2015-liceo/</guid>
      <description>Frequently groups of high-school students come to visit ICTP. One of their standard activities is to attend a short talk by a scientist. A number of times I gave one of these talks. In this case it was a talk for Italian students and I discussed a bit the mathematics of information transmission.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I miss</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/what-i-miss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/what-i-miss/</guid>
      <description>Like a teenager keeping a journal I note in shame that my last post here is from 2012. Since then I have moved to Trieste, Italy, taking a job at the ICTP: Abdus Salam International Centre for Theoretical Physics.&#xA;Horculas en el migo. And so it is.&#xA;Looking back, it is clear that growing up in Buenos Aires shaped my view of the world, what to expect from the day to day of life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impartial Games</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/impartial-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/impartial-games/</guid>
      <description>I gave a the kick-off Basic Notions talk at ICTP in 2014 on Impartial Games (one of the topics of the course Math, Puzzles and Computers).&#xA;I expected students in the class to connect to puzzles and eventually to the corresponding mathematics through a chilhood experience. It is certainly what happened to me while preparing the lectures.&#xA;I have a somewhat vague but powerful memory of being introduced to the standard version of the game of Nim at an early age.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taxi rides</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/taxi-rides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/taxi-rides/</guid>
      <description>I am not sure if it is an Austin phenomenon or not but I have had a few interesting taxi rides back and forth to the airport over the years.&#xA;I’ll leave aside the late night taxi ride where the driver, a young woman, told a few off-color jokes (“you are not a prude man, are you?”); including one that I am pretty sure was popular when I was in primary school.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Character Varieties II</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/tate-abel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/tate-abel/</guid>
      <description>These are the slides of my talk at the first Abel conference in honor of John Tate at the University of Minessota in 2011. It is a summary of my work with T. Hausel and E. Letellier.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back and short</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/back-and-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/back-and-short/</guid>
      <description>I’ve lived in the US now for over 22 years. I have encountered two dollar bills exactly three times (I kept them all). The first time was around Harvard Square as change in a store. It was so strange.&#xA;I’ve seen a few dollar coins too. Usually all of them at once unfortunately. At least 15 years ago, if you bought a NJ transit train ticket in a machine at the station and paid with a 20 dollar bill the change came clanking down in a stream of dollar coins.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puzzlemania</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/puzzles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/puzzles/</guid>
      <description>These are the slides of a talk I gave in the UT Odyssey public lecture series in 2007. It was a partly historical talk on the way certain puzzles seem to grab the public&amp;rsquo;s attention and become an obsession for a period of time, Rubik&amp;rsquo;s cube being a classic example of the recent past. Another wildly popular puzzle was the Famous Trick Donkeys 1858 puzzle by Sam Lloyd.&#xA;The original links on the slides don&amp;rsquo;t seem to work anymore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benasque</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/benasque/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/benasque/</guid>
      <description>While I wait for my brain strings to settle after a long summer shuttling about I make a quick core dump before it’s all gone.&#xA;I spent two weeks in Benasque, Spain for the workshop P-adic analysis, Periods and Physics . We ended up being a very small group of participants, unfortunate in a way but the result was a very charming workshop. And what a place! Benasque is in a valley in the Spanish Pyrenees not far from the border with France, a small mountain town where you walk everywhere, surrounded by amazing mountains full of unbelievably beautiful hikes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dancing Numbers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/dancing-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2007 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/dancing-numbers/</guid>
      <description>I can’t resist one last post before I go off into the webless wilderness of the Atlantic coast. I wasn’t sure what to expect with this blogging idea but I was more than taken aback by how fast the blog’s existence seems to have spread. It’s exciting.&#xA;Over the years I’ve read articles about Twyla Tharp, the american dancer and coreographer. Somehow, I always found great affinity to her ideas. A few months ago, in a New York Times article, she described how she sometimes went for days without dealing with numbers (hid all the clocks in her house, for example) to give the intuitive side of her brain more prominence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math, Puzzles and Computers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/math-puzzles-and-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/math-puzzles-and-computers/</guid>
      <description>In the early 2000&amp;rsquo;s while monkeying around with lattice polygons, I came up with a puzzle that looked interesting. I named it Blet after my daughter Malena saying one day out of the blue: Blet, suena como un tomat. (To this day nobody can really figure out what she meant by it.)&#xA;I discussed the puzzle with my then colleagues at UT, Austin, Felipe Voloch and Lorenzo Sadun, and together worked out pretty much the whole thing and published the results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Morning Math Group</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/smmg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2007 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/smmg/</guid>
      <description>At UT Austin there is a wonderful program of lectures for high-school students on some Saturday mornings. I gave a number of the talks there including one about lattice polygons and the number 12.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Character Varieties I</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/char-var/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2006 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/char-var/</guid>
      <description>These are slides of a talk of the late 2000&amp;rsquo;s (don&amp;rsquo;t remember where) on my early work with T. Hausel on character varieties. It has some details on the combinatorics involved in computing the key quantity $C_\tau$.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complex Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/cplx-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2006 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/cplx-analysis/</guid>
      <description>These are notes of a graduate course in Complex Analysis at UT Austin in 2006. Pretty standard stuff for a first course in Complex Analysis.&#xA;The history of the proof of Cauchy&amp;rsquo;s theorem has its twists and turns. I always liked Goursat&amp;rsquo;s proof that does not require continuity of first partial derivatives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>K-theory and L-functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/k-theory-l-fctns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/k-theory-l-fctns/</guid>
      <description>These are notes (taken by M. Lalín) for a course on $K$-theory and $L$-functions I gave at Harvard University in the Spring of 2002. Notes for the first few lectures were taken by S. Valverde.&#xA;The main goal of the course was to explain how to frame conceptually the numerical examples of D. Boyd relating the Mahler measure of certain two variable polynomials $A(x,y)$ and $L(E,2)$ for $E$ the elliptic curve defined by the zeros of $A$.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Millennium Problems: BSD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/millenial-bsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2001 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/millenial-bsd/</guid>
      <description>Part of the 2001 University of Texas Lectures on the Clay Institute Millennium Problems.&#xA;On the Birch-Swinnerton&amp;ndash;Dyer Conjecture</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La Función Zeta de Hasse-Weil (in Spanish)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/weil-zeta-merida/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 1999 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/weil-zeta-merida/</guid>
      <description>These are notes for a course in Spanish on the Hasse-Weil zeta function given en Mérida, Venezuela in 1999.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mahler Measure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/mahler-measure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 1998 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/mahler-measure/</guid>
      <description>These are the slides of my talk at the 1998 Pacific Northwest Number Theory Meeting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explicit Elliptic Units</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/expl-ell-uts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 1997 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/expl-ell-uts/</guid>
      <description>These are the slides of a talk I gave some time in 1997 on my joint work with Farshid Hajir on defining explicit elliptic units; basically trying, and to some degree succeeding, to tame the 24-th roots of unity that arise from the transformation formula of Dedekind&amp;rsquo;s eta function.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bernoulli Polynomials</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/manuscripts/bernoulli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 1989 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/manuscripts/bernoulli/</guid>
      <description>These are notes on approaching Bernoulli polynomials as eigenvalues of certain operators acting on polynomials. It is my re-interpretation of work of E. H. Lehmer. (A new approach to Bernoulli polynomials, Amer. Math. Monthly 95(1988), 905-911.) I wrote this note at the end of my Ph.D. studies around 1989.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thesis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 1989 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/research-talks/thesis/</guid>
      <description>These are the notes of one my first research talks in the US, at OSU in the Spring of 1989. It is on my thesis (original, published versions).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addition Law on Degenerate Cubics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/manuscripts/degenerate-cubics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 1985 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/manuscripts/degenerate-cubics/</guid>
      <description>These are unpublished notes in Spanish, written in 1985 when I was finishing my undergraduate degree in Buenos Aires, on defining a group law on degenerate cubics. More precisely, on cubics consisting of a smooth conic and a line. Depending on the number of intersection points of the conic and the line over the given ground field (0,1, or 2 points) you get the circle, the additive or the multiplicative group respectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Articles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/math-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/math-articles/</guid>
      <description>Below you can access all my math research articles. Most of them are published but not all.&#xA;Bibliography Quaternionic extensions Rodriguez Villegas, F. (in Spanish). In: Proceedings of the IV Coloquio Latinoamericano De Algebra, Mendoza, Argentina, (1984). Quaternionic extensions and rotations Rodriguez Villegas, F. (In Spanish). Notas De La Sociedad Matemática De Chile, 5(1), 201–202, (1986). Relations between quadratic forms and certain Galois extensions Rodriguez Villegas, F. (Unpublished). (1987). On the square root of special values of certain L-series Rodriguez Villegas, F.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
