<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lattice Polygons on Math Life</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/lattice-polygons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lattice Polygons on Math Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 12:36:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/lattice-polygons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/blet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/blet/</guid>
      <description>In 2018 I was invited by my former ICTP Diploma student Manjil P. Saikia to give a mini-course at the University of Vienna. I also gave a general talk about the puzzle Blet. Later in the year I have a Basic Notions Seminar on the puzzle at ICTP.&#xA;As an experiment I got the transcript of the talk from youtube and then ran it through ChatGPT. After some light editing here is the result.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math, Puzzles and Computers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/math-puzzles-and-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/lecture-notes/math-puzzles-and-computers/</guid>
      <description>In the early 2000&amp;rsquo;s while monkeying around with lattice polygons, I came up with a puzzle that looked interesting. I named it Blet after my daughter Malena saying one day out of the blue: Blet, suena como un tomat. (To this day nobody can really figure out what she meant by it.)&#xA;I discussed the puzzle with my then colleagues at UT, Austin, Felipe Voloch and Lorenzo Sadun, and together worked out pretty much the whole thing and published the results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Morning Math Group</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/smmg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2007 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/public-lectures/smmg/</guid>
      <description>At UT Austin there is a wonderful program of lectures for high-school students on some Saturday mornings. I gave a number of the talks there including one about lattice polygons and the number 12.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
