<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Photography on Math Life</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/photography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Photography on Math Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 10:00:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/photography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oxford</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/oxford/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/oxford/</guid>
      <description>I was back in Oxford to give a talk at the workshop on The P=W Conjecture in Non Abelian Hodge Theory, part of the Clay Mathematical Institute conference of 2024.&#xA;I arrived a day early, on Saturday, and spent the day walking around town remembering the old days (2009-2010 when I visited for the year). There was some kind of graduation ceremony happening and though I don&amp;rsquo;t really like to take pictures of people I could not resist this one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MFO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/mfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/mfo/</guid>
      <description>I have been going to Oberwolfach for a number of years now, twice for two weeks at a time in the Research in Pairs scheme. What an incredible place, a real gem.&#xA;MFO </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saxes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/saxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/saxes/</guid>
      <description>Walking to the riva after getting gelato at Marco. Maybe these musicians were part of the ensemble playing on the temporary stage on Piazza Unita related to the Pope&amp;rsquo;s visit to Trieste. Enjoying the sun and the ocean breeze during a break.&#xA;Saxes </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Something about cheese</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/something-about-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/something-about-cheese/</guid>
      <description>I love this picture.&#xA;Early in the morning in the Barrio Gotico of Barcelona. As I walked by I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help hearing part of the conversation. The young woman seemed to be asking in good but accented Spanish where she could find a particular kind of cheese. I imagine she thought the old ladies were locals that would know.&#xA;Something about cheese </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/boat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/boat/</guid>
      <description>I think this is the first picture I took focusing on a reflected image in water. I liked the way the masts of the boats (straight, solid, crucial to their life) appeared in this surrealistic, impressionistic way. Since then when walking around Trieste near the sea or the canal I always look at the scenes reflected on their surface and often take a picture. It is now trivial to rotate and flip the picture so we get a interesting view from a very weird angle.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
