<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Math Life</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Math Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 10:00:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>C&#39;est le moment des braves: Goodbye Karim</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/karim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/karim/</guid>
      <description>C’est le moment des braves&#xA;So would Karim write to Ralph at precisely midday, to say it was time for lunch. Every working day for years.&#xA;So Ralph told us, the many people crammed in the Parrochia di San Michele Arcangelo in Sgonico, during Karim’s funeral. A laic ceremony.&#xA;Outside, the massive trees with their large yellowing leaves were already in winter. The air was wet. The bright yellow contrasted with the dark color of people’s clothes and the heavy silence and the concentrated and sad look of people’s faces.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Zealand II: Arthur&#39;s Pass</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/new-zealand-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/new-zealand-2/</guid>
      <description>New Zealand is a wild place.&#xA;As far as we know humans only settled in New Zealand in the 13th century AD. They were Polynesians who came in canoes from small Pacific islands far away to the East. There were no land mammals except for some small bats. The Polynesians brought with them rats and dogs and various crops, some of which grew in New Zealand and became staple foods (including, famously, kūmara, the sweet potato, a major historical puzzle).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Zealand I: Christchurch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/new-zealand-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/new-zealand-1/</guid>
      <description>It’s now about two weeks since I arrived in Christchurch, New Zealand. I am here as an Erskine Fellow teaching the first half of an undergraduate course on Coding Theory at the University of Canterbury.&#xA;The city is quite large and very spread out. It reminds me in different ways of both the UK and the US. Not having a car is fairly limiting though the bus system is good. Everyone gives a big “Thank you!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water and Ice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/water-and-ice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/water-and-ice/</guid>
      <description>Water and ice En un sueño lejano,&#xA;como un recuerdo en la niebla,&#xA;aparece Borges.&#xA;Escritor de Buenos Aires, ciego.&#xA;Escritor no del amor sino del espanto.&#xA;Aparece como el capitán de un equipo de rugby&#xA;arengando a sus compañeros en el vestuario:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Muchachos, a ver si nos entendemos,&#xA;el hielo existe&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Transición de fase lo llaman los físicos,&#xA;como la muerte.&#xA;Un día sos, al otro día no.&#xA;El agua fluye, el hielo se queda donde está.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belluno</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/belluno/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/belluno/</guid>
      <description>En Belluno para el bendito PET. Casi cuatro horas de tren desde Trieste. Lindo paisaje de montaña, nieve en las cimas a lo lejos.&#xA;Belluno bonita en el sol brillante y el aire límpido. Claramente del Veneto, extraño Venezia en las montañas. Piazza dei Martiri antes fuera delle mura de la ciudad. Un cono de nieve sucia a la sombra de unos árboles en la plaza. Piazza arcuata, edificios en curva a 92 m de la muralla, dos metros mas que el alcance de los arcabuses de la época.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to eat a maritozzo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/how-to-eat-a-maritozzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/how-to-eat-a-maritozzo/</guid>
      <description>The first thing to understand is that the question of the title is not a trivial one, especially if you have a beard.&#xA;So what is a maritozzo? It&amp;rsquo;s a Roman pastry consisting of a ball of sweet bread with a big gash in the middle completely filled with whipped cream. The New York Times calls them unnapealingly &amp;ldquo;Sweet Cream Buns&amp;rdquo;, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t even begin to do them justice. It seems that maritozzi have become quite a thing in the US from what I can gather online.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two nights at Cattinara (in Spanish)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/two-nights-at-cattinara/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/two-nights-at-cattinara/</guid>
      <description>En junio de 2023 al volver de un viaje a Viena y Amsterdam empecé con síntomas de un resfrío fuerte. Pero la fiebre no bajaba y después de unos días llamamos al servicio médico. Terminé yendo en ambulancia al pronto soccorso del Ospedale di Cattinara en Trieste. Tenía una fea pulmonía.&#xA;Mientras estuve en el hospital escribí las notas que siguen.&#xA;Me llama mucho la atención las jerarquías dentro del hospital marcadas por uniformes de varios colores.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Randomness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/on-randomness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/on-randomness/</guid>
      <description>Iperborea is an italian publishing house founded by Emilia Lodigiani in 1987 which aims to bring to Italian readers the literature of northern Europe. Their books have a distinctive format and texture of their covers making them instantly recognizable while browsing in a bookstore. Not all of their titles are easy to find in English in Italy so they are a good way for me to connect to Scandinavian culture while also practicing my Italian.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamilton and the Discovery of Quaternions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/hamilton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/hamilton/</guid>
      <description>Towards the end of my Ph.D. years at The Ohio State University together with a bunch of graduate students we thought of publishing our own magazine. We struggled to come up with a good name for it so after a lot of back and forth we settled on &amp;ldquo;The Empy Set&amp;rdquo;. The OSU graduate advisor found this too nihilistic and wanted us to pick a different name. We nevertheless wrote what inevitably ended up being the only issue of &amp;ldquo;The Empty Set&amp;rdquo; and circulated it among the department.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Large Language Model in the 1700s?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/jonathan-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/jonathan-swift/</guid>
      <description>I listened to a fascinating podcast in the &amp;ldquo;Past, Present, Future&amp;rdquo; series by David Runciman on the 1726 satire &amp;ldquo;Gulliver&amp;rsquo;s Travels&amp;rdquo; by Jonathan Swift. Runciman gives an excellent summary of the various journeys that Gulliver undertakes in this book; journeys to far away lands were he encounters fantastic creatures and their world: tiny people, giants, talking horses, and the like.&#xA;In one of these journeys Gulliver finds academics stubbornly determined to strip language of all ambiguity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Figs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/figs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 12:36:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/figs/</guid>
      <description>Let’s talk figs.&#xA;There was a fig tree near the main house “Villa Isaura” in Carlos Paz, Cordoba where I spent many a holiday as a kid. I remember breaking off leaves to see and feel the white sticky substance that came out. It was a somewhat mysterious and out of the way tree, with strange gnarly branches and big dark green leaves, a huge contrast to the tall, straight and ubiquitous eucalyptus trees that lined up so many sidewalks of my Buenos Aires childhood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From here to there</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/from-here-to-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/from-here-to-there/</guid>
      <description>One of the odd perks of getting old is that one can look back to the distant past and wonder with cold detachment just who the hell we were.&#xA;As a kid I was obsessed with cryptography and secret messages. I even halfheartedly tried to create a language that only my friends and I would understand. I wanted to build a robot. I also wanted to live in a desert island and made endless plans in my head on how I would run my life on it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I miss</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/what-i-miss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/what-i-miss/</guid>
      <description>Like a teenager keeping a journal I note in shame that my last post here is from 2012. Since then I have moved to Trieste, Italy, taking a job at the ICTP: Abdus Salam International Centre for Theoretical Physics.&#xA;Horculas en el migo. And so it is.&#xA;Looking back, it is clear that growing up in Buenos Aires shaped my view of the world, what to expect from the day to day of life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taxi rides</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/taxi-rides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/taxi-rides/</guid>
      <description>I am not sure if it is an Austin phenomenon or not but I have had a few interesting taxi rides back and forth to the airport over the years.&#xA;I’ll leave aside the late night taxi ride where the driver, a young woman, told a few off-color jokes (“you are not a prude man, are you?”); including one that I am pretty sure was popular when I was in primary school.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back and short</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/back-and-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/back-and-short/</guid>
      <description>I’ve lived in the US now for over 22 years. I have encountered two dollar bills exactly three times (I kept them all). The first time was around Harvard Square as change in a store. It was so strange.&#xA;I’ve seen a few dollar coins too. Usually all of them at once unfortunately. At least 15 years ago, if you bought a NJ transit train ticket in a machine at the station and paid with a 20 dollar bill the change came clanking down in a stream of dollar coins.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benasque</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/benasque/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/benasque/</guid>
      <description>While I wait for my brain strings to settle after a long summer shuttling about I make a quick core dump before it’s all gone.&#xA;I spent two weeks in Benasque, Spain for the workshop P-adic analysis, Periods and Physics . We ended up being a very small group of participants, unfortunate in a way but the result was a very charming workshop. And what a place! Benasque is in a valley in the Spanish Pyrenees not far from the border with France, a small mountain town where you walk everywhere, surrounded by amazing mountains full of unbelievably beautiful hikes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dancing Numbers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/dancing-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2007 10:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/dancing-numbers/</guid>
      <description>I can’t resist one last post before I go off into the webless wilderness of the Atlantic coast. I wasn’t sure what to expect with this blogging idea but I was more than taken aback by how fast the blog’s existence seems to have spread. It’s exciting.&#xA;Over the years I’ve read articles about Twyla Tharp, the american dancer and coreographer. Somehow, I always found great affinity to her ideas. A few months ago, in a New York Times article, she described how she sometimes went for days without dealing with numbers (hid all the clocks in her house, for example) to give the intuitive side of her brain more prominence.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
